<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://jhmartel.github.io/fp/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://jhmartel.github.io/fp/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-02-12T09:18:38-06:00</updated><id>https://jhmartel.github.io/fp/feed.xml</id><title type="html">JHM Lab.</title><subtitle>Optimal Transport, Topology of Singularities, Physics.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">How to Start a Jewellery Business</title><link href="https://jhmartel.github.io/fp/2023/02/12/RingMaking.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Start a Jewellery Business" /><published>2023-02-12T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-02-12T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://jhmartel.github.io/fp/2023/02/12/RingMaking</id><author><name>JHM</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[JHM Labs has begun a new project in something completely different. We have realized that JHM Labs has all the elements required to start a modern day jewellery business. At this stage we are planning out work flows and building prototypes.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Decide when Curves Self Intersect in the Universal Cover</title><link href="https://jhmartel.github.io/fp/2023/02/04/BriefCommentMCGWhenAreCurvesDisjoint.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Decide when Curves Self Intersect in the Universal Cover" /><published>2023-02-04T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-02-04T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://jhmartel.github.io/fp/2023/02/04/BriefCommentMCGWhenAreCurvesDisjoint</id><author><name>JHM</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[JHM Labs has been working intensively on Weber, but we briefly return to the problem of Closing Steinberg on the mapping class group of hyperbolic surfaces. In this post we comment on the technical lemma which is delaying our progress. The question is How does one really decide whether curves in the universal cover project to simple closed curves, with emphasis on simple? Or equivalently, How to decide when the $G$ translates of a doubly ended infinite geodesic $ll$ are disjoint in the universal cover? This is interesting decision problem, and serves as the prototype of a more general problem related to applications of solutions to Closing Steinberg.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Chain Rule and Calculus of Relational Mechanics.</title><link href="https://jhmartel.github.io/fp/2023/02/02/RelationalChainRuleIdentitiesl.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chain Rule and Calculus of Relational Mechanics." /><published>2023-02-02T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-02-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://jhmartel.github.io/fp/2023/02/02/RelationalChainRuleIdentitiesl</id><author><name>JHM</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We continue to develop the $N$ body Weber systems. Integrating the equations of motion requires a relational formulation of Hamilton's equations for the Weber Newton system. In this post we make simple comments on an interesting pseudo partial derivative which arise in applications. We would expect a Kronecker delta, but the reality is somewhat different. For calculus of relational mechanics this is very important basic computation, so must eventually be addressed by any practitioner.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Weber Hamilton Two Body Equations. Again.</title><link href="https://jhmartel.github.io/fp/2023/01/28/WeberHamiltonTwoBodyAgain.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Weber Hamilton Two Body Equations. Again." /><published>2023-01-28T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-01-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://jhmartel.github.io/fp/2023/01/28/WeberHamiltonTwoBodyAgain</id><author><name>JHM</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We have to make absolutely clear the derivation of the ODE representing Weber Hamilton system. Here we only treat the two-body case, although we continue to slowly count 2,3,4,5,6, towards the question of whether Bohr is really more energetically probable than Weber-Sansbury's models.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bohr versus Weber-Sansbury Planetary Model of Hydrogen</title><link href="https://jhmartel.github.io/fp/2023/01/26/isBohrMoreProbableThanWeberSansbury.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bohr versus Weber-Sansbury Planetary Model of Hydrogen" /><published>2023-01-26T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-01-26T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://jhmartel.github.io/fp/2023/01/26/isBohrMoreProbableThanWeberSansbury</id><author><name>JHM</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[[Chaos Post: Everything Under Construction] A simple question with non obvious answer. Which model is more probable, Bohr's or Sansbury's? It's a billion dollar question. This post has alot of words but not enough calculations. We need to figure out the correct KDK integration scheme for Weber's potential, and this is work in progress. Remember that nobody has seen the atom, and it is essentially unseeable since it does not radiate energy to the environment. But it's perhaps more structured than classical and quantum theories allow.]]></summary></entry></feed>