<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://jhmartel.github.io/fp/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://jhmartel.github.io/fp/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-10-16T09:28:20-05:00</updated><id>https://jhmartel.github.io/fp/feed.xml</id><title type="html">JHM Lab.</title><subtitle>Optimal Transport, Topology of Singularities, Physics.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">How to Stabilize Blum’s Medial Axis Transform.</title><link href="https://jhmartel.github.io/fp/fastpages/jupyter/2022/10/15/StabilizingMAT.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Stabilize Blum’s Medial Axis Transform." /><published>2022-10-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-10-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://jhmartel.github.io/fp/fastpages/jupyter/2022/10/15/StabilizingMAT</id><author><name>JHM</name></author><category term="fastpages" /><category term="jupyter" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Brief remark on stabilizing the medial axis transform M(A) of open subsets A of Rn. The basic idea is to use the Reduction-to-Singularity method from our thesis to define homotopy-reductions M(A) to W(A). This is speculative and not formally proven at this stage.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Weber-Kirchoff’s Response to Veritasium’s Huge Circuit Problem</title><link href="https://jhmartel.github.io/fp/2022/10/08/Veritasium_Response.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Weber-Kirchoff’s Response to Veritasium’s Huge Circuit Problem" /><published>2022-10-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-10-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://jhmartel.github.io/fp/2022/10/08/Veritasium_Response</id><author><name>JHM</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this post we present what we believe Weber and Kirchoff's solution to Veritasium's video on electricity. This video caused surprising uproar from physicists and engineers. The surprising degree of controversy is indicative a deep misunderstanding underlying electromagnetism, and this is where Weber-Kirchoff's original idea of surface charge distributions proportional to voltage being the cause of steady state currents in resistive wires. We recall that Weber and Kirchoff are the first scientists to derive the telegraphy equation, which predicts that electrical signals in conductive wires travel at the speed of light $c$. This is important work even prior to Maxwell's equations.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Deciding Injectivity and C.A.Feinstein’s Proposed Negative Solution to P vs NP.</title><link href="https://jhmartel.github.io/fp/2022/10/06/Feinstein_Part2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Deciding Injectivity and C.A.Feinstein’s Proposed Negative Solution to P vs NP." /><published>2022-10-06T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-10-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://jhmartel.github.io/fp/2022/10/06/Feinstein_Part2</id><author><name>JHM</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We continue to review and reflect on questions suggested by Craig Alan Feinstein's proposed negative solution to P versus NP. We are specifically reflecting on a signed subset sum problem, which is effectively a linearization of the unsigned subset sum. The question then reduces to deciding the injectivity of a map, namely from a large dimensional finite object to a much smaller dimensional but infinite object, namely integers. This raises the question of what is the computational complexity of deciding injectivity of maps? Is it really ever possible to deterministically decide the injectivity of a map without necessarily running through every evaluation? Along the way we discuss several aspects of CAF's work.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Computational Complexity of Fibonacci Sequences. Part 1.</title><link href="https://jhmartel.github.io/fp/2022/10/04/Fibonacci_Complexity.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Computational Complexity of Fibonacci Sequences. Part 1." /><published>2022-10-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-10-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://jhmartel.github.io/fp/2022/10/04/Fibonacci_Complexity</id><author><name>JHM</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We revisit the well known subject of the computational complexity of Fibonacci's sequence 1, 1, 2, 3, 5, 8, 13, etc.. However we are looking at the question with Wolfram's idea of computational irreducibility. Yet Wolfram does not appear to define irreducibility, and this suggests the question of relating topological irreducibility to questions of computation, and this is somewhat speculative, as we are looking for strategies to prove that O(log(n)) is the minimal time complexity of computing fibonacci sequences. Can we formalize Wolfram's definition and obtain a strategy for proving the minimality of these running times? We're curious and this is exploration.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">[Update] Weber Two Body Problem with Python and Gekko</title><link href="https://jhmartel.github.io/fp/fastpages/jupyter/2022/09/13/Weber_TwoBody_Ctd.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="[Update] Weber Two Body Problem with Python and Gekko" /><published>2022-09-13T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-09-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://jhmartel.github.io/fp/fastpages/jupyter/2022/09/13/Weber_TwoBody_Ctd</id><author><name>JHM</name></author><category term="fastpages" /><category term="jupyter" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this post we present the basic python and gekko code for simulating two negatively charged electrons acting under Weber's force. The challenge is to obtain bounded orbits, i.e. to witness electrons passing the Weber critical radius and becoming attractive. As we've discussed in previous posts, this requires high energy levels comparable to the famous $E=m c^2$ formula.]]></summary></entry></feed>