<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://jhmartel.github.io/fp/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://jhmartel.github.io/fp/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-10-06T15:26:28-05:00</updated><id>https://jhmartel.github.io/fp/feed.xml</id><title type="html">JHM Lab.</title><subtitle>Optimal Transport, Topology of Singularities, Physics.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Deciding Injectivity and C.A.Feinstein’s Proposed Negative Solution to P versus NP.</title><link href="https://jhmartel.github.io/fp/2022/10/06/Feinstein_Part2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Deciding Injectivity and C.A.Feinstein’s Proposed Negative Solution to P versus NP." /><published>2022-10-06T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-10-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://jhmartel.github.io/fp/2022/10/06/Feinstein_Part2</id><author><name>JHM[link text](https://)</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We continue to review and reflect on questions suggested by Craig Alan Feinstein's proposed negative solution to P versus NP. We are specifically reflecting on a signed subset sum problem, which is effectively a linearization of the unsigned subset sum. But then the question reduces to deciding the injectivity of a linear map, namely from a large dimensional vector space to a much smaller dimensional vector space. This raises the question of what is the computational complexity of deciding injectivity of linear maps? Is it really ever possible to deterministically decide the injectivity of a map without necessarily running through every evaluation?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Computational Complexity of Fibonacci Sequences. Part 1.</title><link href="https://jhmartel.github.io/fp/2022/10/04/Fibonacci_Complexity.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Computational Complexity of Fibonacci Sequences. Part 1." /><published>2022-10-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-10-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://jhmartel.github.io/fp/2022/10/04/Fibonacci_Complexity</id><author><name>JHM</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We revisit the well known subject of the computational complexity of Fibonacci's sequence 1, 1, 2, 3, 5, 8, 13, etc.. However we are looking at the question with Wolfram's idea of computational irreducibility. Yet Wolfram does not appear to define irreducibility, and this suggests the question of relating topological irreducibility to questions of computation, and this is somewhat speculative, as we are looking for strategies to prove that O(log(n)) is the minimal time complexity of computing fibonacci sequences. Can we formalize Wolfram's definition and obtain a strategy for proving the minimality of these running times? We're curious and this is exploration.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">[Update] Weber Two Body Problem with Python and Gekko</title><link href="https://jhmartel.github.io/fp/fastpages/jupyter/2022/09/13/Weber_TwoBody_Ctd.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="[Update] Weber Two Body Problem with Python and Gekko" /><published>2022-09-13T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-09-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://jhmartel.github.io/fp/fastpages/jupyter/2022/09/13/Weber_TwoBody_Ctd</id><author><name>JHM</name></author><category term="fastpages" /><category term="jupyter" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this post we present the basic python and gekko code for simulating two negatively charged electrons acting under Weber's force. The challenge is to obtain bounded orbits, i.e. to witness electrons passing the Weber critical radius and becoming attractive. As we've discussed in previous posts, this requires high energy levels comparable to the famous $E=m c^2$ formula.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">[Under Construction] Weber Three Body Problem.</title><link href="https://jhmartel.github.io/fp/fastpages/jupyter/2022/09/11/WeberThreeBody.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="[Under Construction] Weber Three Body Problem." /><published>2022-09-11T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-09-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://jhmartel.github.io/fp/fastpages/jupyter/2022/09/11/WeberThreeBody</id><author><name>JHM</name></author><category term="fastpages" /><category term="jupyter" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Our goal in this post is to integrate the equations of motion for three charged bodies under Weber's force law. Why? Because we want to test the Sansbury proposal that the electron $e^{-}$ is structured, specifically as a 3-body system with net charge -1=-1-1+1. Yes, this is strange hypothesis and very important to investigate. But there is a challenge: the Newtonian equations of motion combined with Weber force are not the usual second order ODEs. This means we need to introduce a Differential Algebraic Equation (DAE) solver named GEKKO, and this has delayed the publication of this post. With GEKKO we can solve ODEs of the form $F(x, x', x'')=0$. This post is theoretical. But we are working on the python notebooks for the actual code for Weber 3-body problem with net charge -1 = -1 -1 + 1.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">[Under Construction] Weber Sansbury’s Structured Planetary Model of the Atom</title><link href="https://jhmartel.github.io/fp/fastpages/jupyter/2022/09/04/WeberPlanetaryModel.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="[Under Construction] Weber Sansbury’s Structured Planetary Model of the Atom" /><published>2022-09-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-09-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://jhmartel.github.io/fp/fastpages/jupyter/2022/09/04/WeberPlanetaryModel</id><author><name>JHM</name></author><category term="fastpages" /><category term="jupyter" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bohr and quantum mechanics never explained the apparent nonradiation of the hydrogen atom. It was instead postulated, taken as given, and led to the quantum discontinuities, etc... But the great Wilhelm Weber (1804-1891) and the quiet softspoken Ralph Sansbury have a very interesting alternative, which answers everything that Bohr and Quantum could not, and succeeds where they surrendered, which is explaining the stability of atoms.]]></summary></entry></feed>